inficon.com 2019-07-30

# Privacy Statement - INFICON

##  Privacy Policy 

INFICON (“we” or “us”) welcomes your visit to our website (the “Site”) and your interest in our Company and our products and services. We take the protection of your personal data seriously, and we would like you to feel secure during your visit to our Site. The protection of your privacy during the processing of personal data is a key concern for us, which we consider in our business processes.

We process personal data which is collected during a user’s visit to our Site in accordance with the privacy and data protection regulations of the country in which the site responsible for the data processing is located.  The name and contact details of the data controller (hereafter referred to as "INFICON") can be found at the end of this document.

INFICON’s website may contain links to the websites of other providers, which are not covered by this Privacy Policy.  When you link to other websites from our Site, INFICON’s privacy practices no longer apply, and we do not warrant, represent or assume any responsibility or liability for the accuracy, security, completeness or operation of any linked site or any site contained in a linked site. 

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you about the types of information we might collect about you when you visit our Site, how we may use that information and whether we disclose that information to anyone. By using our Site, you acknowledge and agree to be bound to the terms hereof.  Periodically, we may update this Privacy Policy and encourage you to check this section for any changes.

 **1\. Terms of Use**

The contents of this Site are provided by INFICON solely for personal and non-commercial purposes. The use of the INFICON Site for public and commercial purposes (including but not limited to usage on another website or in a computer network) is strictly prohibited.

As a service provider, INFICON is responsible for its own content on the INFICON websites according to the general laws in accordance with § 7 (1) of the German Telemedia Act (TMG). According to §§ 8 to 10 TMG, however, INFICON as a service provider is not obliged to monitor transmitted or stored external information or to investigate circumstances that indicate illegal activity. Obligations to remove or block the use of information under general law remain unaffected. Liability in this regard, however, is only possible from the date of the awareness of a specific legal violation. Upon notification of such violations INFICON will remove this content immediately.

INFICON websites may contain direct or indirect references to other websites (hereinafter referred to as the "links") outside INFICON's area of responsibility. This Privacy Statement does not extend to such contents of other providers. INFICON declares that at the time the links were established, no illegal content was detected on the linked pages. INFICON has no influence on the current and future design, contents or authorship of the linked pages. For illegal, incorrect or incomplete contents and in particular for damages resulting from the use or non-use of such information presented, only the provider of the website referred to is liable, not the party which refers to its particular publication via links.

Our Site contains material and contents associated with INFICON products and services. These contents include texts, data, graphics, logos, button icons, illustrations, audio and video clips, hyperlinks, digital downloads, software downloads and data compilations. All contents on our Site are owned by INFICON and are protected by copyright, trademark or other intellectual property rights. If you reproduce contents contained on our Site with our prior permission, the corresponding copyrights or property rights of the source materials must be indicated on all copies. You are not permitted to alter, publicly display, publicly perform or disseminate these contents. The unauthorized use of contents contained in our Site may infringe copyrights, trademark rights and violate data protection regulations. INFICON and the INFICON logo are registered trademarks of INFICON Holding AG and may not be used without the written permission of INFICON. You may obtain a complete list of the trademarks held by INFICON upon inquiry at: [reachus@inficon.com](mailto:reachus@inficon.com). All other trademarks on our Site are the property of their respective owners.

INFICON does not guarantee the timeliness, correctness, completeness or quality of the information provided. Liability claims against INFICON, which relate to material or immaterial damages caused by the use or non-use of the information presented, are excluded, unless INFICON has proven to be intentionally or grossly negligent.

INFICON expressly reserves the right to change, supplement or delete parts of the web pages or the entire website without a separate notice or to cease publication temporarily or permanently.

 **2\. Collection and Processing of General Data and Information**

When you visit our Site, our web server stores a range of general data and information in the log files of our server that is not of a personal nature, but is collected about your visit, including, for example, the pages you view, the features you use, the links you click and other actions you take in connection with our Site. The purpose of the foregoing is so that we can enhance the delivery of the contents of our Site in a manner that optimizes its utility and helps us deliver information to you.  It also helps us to determine the effectiveness of our advertising, in addition to other internal business purposes. In addition, we use such general data to ensure the lasting functionality of our information technology system and the technology of our Site, and in the event of a cyber attack, to provide the regulatory authorities with the information needed for prosecution.  

All such general data and information is collected on an anonymous basis without identification to a particular user.  Examples of such general data and information may include your (1) browser type and versions used, (2) your operating system, (3) the identity of the websites you visit immediately before coming to our Site, (4) the sub-websites which are controlled by a system accessing our Site, (5) the date and time of your access to our Site and (6) your computer’s Internet Protocol address (IP address) assigned to you by your Internet service provider.

With the exception of your IP address, we do not require anyone to share any of their personal information with us in order to enjoy our Site.  Personal data is only collected if you specifically and voluntarily provide it to us on our Site (e.g., as part of a registration, a survey, a prize competition, an information inquiry or the implementation of a contract).Storage of these data together with other personal data of the user does not take place.

The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 (1) (1) ( f) GDPR. INFICON's legitimate interest in data processing follows from the purposes listed above. In no case do we use the collected data for the purpose of drawing conclusions about you.

Furthermore, we use cookies and analysis services during visits to our website. Further details can be found in paragraphs 3, 10 and 11 of this Data Protection Statement.

 **3\. Use of Cookies**

Our Site uses “cookies.” Cookies are small text files written by an Internet server that are stored in an Internet browser or by the Internet browser on a user’s computer system where information is exchanged between them. They are used by us in providing a more customized website experience.  It is INFICON’s policy to use cookies to make navigation of our Site easier for our visitors and to facilitate easier registration procedures.

Some elements of our webpage require that the accessing browser can still be identified, even after changing pages. In the cookies (1) the language setting, (2) the items in a basket and (3) the log-in information are collected and transmitted.

Furthermore, we use cookies on our website to allow analysis of the users’ surfing patterns. This covers, for example, (1) the entered search terms, (2) the frequency of page views and (3) the use of website functions.

The legal basis for the processing of the personal data collected by cookies is in Art. 6 (1) (1) (b) GDPR (processing for the execution of a contract or pre-contractual measures), insofar as this relates to possible orders or other contractual relationships with INFICON (shopping cart, log-in), otherwise in Art. 6 (1) (1) (f) GDPR. The legitimate interest results from the purposes mentioned in the first paragraph above.

The user data collected this way are pseudonymized by means of technical precautions. Therefore, assignment of the data to the user is no longer possible. When stored, the data are not aggregated with other users’ personal data.

When visiting our Site, an information banner will inform you about our use of cookies for analytical purposes.

If you are concerned about cookies and do not want them placed on your computer, you can disable cookies on your browser before using our Site. You can find details in your browser instructions. Your use of our Site may be limited without the aid of cookies. 

 **4\. Registration on Our Internet Website**

On our Site, we offer you the option to register with us by giving certain kinds of personal information. Registration in the input masks provided on our Site is required to keep specific contents and services available for use on our Site. If you choose to register with us, we collect only personally identifiable information that you voluntarily provide to us.  Such personally identifiable information may include your name, company name, address, email address, and telephone and fax numbers that are needed to administer our business, allow you to utilize the full capabilities of our Site and to permit us to communicate information to you relative to our products and services that we believe may be of interest to you and our website visitors.  By registering on our Site (1) your IP address, (2) the date, (3) the time of your registration and (4) the country from which you are registering are also stored.

The legal basis of this data processing is Art. 6 (1) (1) (a) GDPR. Registered individuals have the option to change the personal data provided or to have it deleted completely from the database at any time.

As part of the registration process, a user’s permission is obtained to process such data. Registered individuals have the option to change their personal data provided or to have it deleted completely from our database at any time.

 **5\. Use of Personal Information and** **Purpose Limitation**

We use your personal information for a number of purposes, including, technical administration of our Site, customer and prospective customer administration, for providing you with surveys and company information, as well as for marketing purposes to communicate with you.

We would like to inform you in the best possible way about our products and services and to request your opinion, where applicable. Of course, participation in such campaigns is voluntary.

 **6\. Newsletter**

You may also subscribe to a newsletter on our Site free of charge. The personal data that will be transmitted when ordering our newsletter can be found in the corresponding input masks on our Site. Your permission is obtained to process the data as part of the enrollment process. The legal basis for the relevant data processing is Art. 6 (1) (1) (a) GDPR.

Signing up for our newsletter takes place in a so-called double opt-in procedure (i.e., after the enrollment, you will receive an e-mail in which you are asked to confirm the enrollment). This confirmation is necessary so that no one with unknown e-mail addresses can enroll.

During the enrollment process (1) your IP address, (2) the date, (3) the time of your registration and (4) the country from which you accessing our Site are again stored by us. Such data that you provide will be used only for sending you our newsletter, unless and until you choose to unsubscribe. 

You can unsubscribe at any time through our Site by following the “unsubscribe” instructions that are available on our Site or by contacting us, as provided below.

You are entitled to revoke the consent statement provided through double opt-in procedure at any time. After a revocation, these personal data will be deleted by us. INFICON interprets a cancellation of the receipt of the newsletter as a revocation of the consent.

INFICON currently uses “[MailChimp](https://mailchimp.com/)”, a newsletter distribution platform of the US provider, the Rocket Science Group, to send out INFICON’s newsletters. You can view the data protection provisions of MailChimp at: <https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy>. The e-mail addresses of our newsletter recipients as well as their data described as part of these directions are stored on the MailChimp servers in the USA. MailChimp uses this Information to distribute and analyze the newsletter on our behalf as part of order processing pursuant to Art. 28 (3) GDPR. Furthermore, according to its own information, MailChimp can use these data to optimize or improve its own services, e.g., for technical optimization of the distribution and the presentation of the newsletter or for commercial purposes to determine the countries the recipients come from. MailChimp, however, does not use the data of our newsletter recipients to contact them itself or to pass the data on to third parties. MailChimp is certified under the US-EU Data Protection Agreement “Privacy Shield” and thus is obligated to comply with the EU data protection requirements.

 **7\. Newsletter Tracking**

INFICON newsletters contain analytical methods, (e.g., tracking pixels). As a result, a statistical analysis of the success or lack of success of online marketing campaigns can be conducted. Using these analytical methods, INFICON can detect whether and when an e-mail of a data subject was opened and which links in the e-mail of the data subject were activated.

Such personal data can be stored and analyzed to optimize our newsletter distribution and to adapt more effectively the content of future newsletters. The legal basis for the relevant data processing is Art. 6 (1) (1) ( f) GDPR. Such personal data is not disclosed by INFICON to third parties except as otherwise expressly permitted herein.

 **8\. Contact Option via the Website**

A contact form is available on our Site, which can be used for making contact with us electronically. By means of the input mask, personal data including (1) your IP address, (2) the date and (3) time are transmitted to us on a voluntary basis and stored automatically for purposes of processing or making contact.

Alternatively, contact is possible via any e-mail address provided by you to INFICON. In this case, any personal data transmitted with the e-mail is stored. The data is then used exclusively for processing any contacts between us. The legal basis in this respect is Art. 6 (1) (1) (b) GDPR.

Again, INFICON does not disclose any such personal data to third parties except as expressly permitted herein.

 **9\. Disclosure of** **Personal Data**

On rare occasions, we may be required to disclose your information as is required by law pursuant to lawful requests such as subpoenas, court orders or as we may reasonably determine to be necessary to protect our rights or the rights of others, to avert harm to persons or property, or to enforce this Privacy Policy. The legal basis in this respect is Art. 6 (1) (1) (c) GDPR. Disclosures of personal data may also be required to be made to state institutions and officials within the scope of mandatory national regulations. We require our employees, agencies and dealers to maintain confidentiality.

Aside from the foregoing, your personal data is not passed on, sold or otherwise transmitted to third parties unless it is deemed reasonably necessary for business purposes or for the purposes of executing a contract or you have explicitly consented to such activities. Thus, for example, when products or services are ordered, it may be necessary for us to pass on your address and order data to our contractual partners or as part of the hiring of special service providers that support us during our activities. The legal basis for the processing of your personal data is Art. 6 (1) (1) (a) GDPR, insofar as you have given your consent, otherwise Art. 6 (1) (1) (b) GDPR.

When executing a contract through our Web Shop, by executing, you hereby consent to our sending of your personal data to process the payment transactions via a credit card, direct debit or other payment methods to service providers, which may process and store your personal data, send your personal data to such sites necessary to process the transaction, such as participating credit institutions, banks and credit card institutions. The legal basis of the data processing is insofar Art. 6 (1) (1) (a) GDPR.

 **10\. Social Plug-ins**

From time to time, we use so-called social plug-ins (hereafter, “buttons”) of social networks such as Facebook, Twitter, Google+, YouTube, Instagram and LinkedIn.

During your visit to our Site, these buttons are normally deactivated (i.e., they send no data to the respective social networks without your assistance). Before you can use the buttons, you must activate them by clicking on them. The buttons remain active until you deactivate them again or delete your cookies. After activation, a direct connection with the server of the applicable social network is established. The contents of the button are then transferred by the social networks directly to your browser and embedded by it in the website. If you are logged into a social network, it can allocate your visit to this website to your user account. If you are a member of a social network and would not like it to link the data collected during your visit to our website to your stored member data, you must log out of the respective social network before using our website.

We have no impact on the scope of the data collected by the social networks with the buttons. Please find the purpose and extent of the data collection and the further processing and use of the data by the respective social networks as well as your rights in this regard and setting options for protecting your privacy in the data protection information of the respective social networks. (Facebook and Instagram: <https://www.facebook.com/policy.php>. Twitter: <https://twitter.com/privacy>; Google+ and YouTube: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>; LinkedIn: <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>). If the social media providers are US companies, they are each certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement to ensure that they maintain an adequate data protection level (<https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>).

 **11\. Analysis of Usage Data**

We would like to continually update our offering of products and services to you and improve our online services. That is why we use the following technologies to identify the preferences of visitors and especially popular areas of our Internet offering. This way we can tailor the contents of our Internet website more closely to your needs and -  if necessary – eliminate any errors more quickly.

Google Analytics:

Google Analytics is a Web analysis service of Google Inc., USA (hereafter: Google). Web analysis is the surveying, collection and evaluation of data about the behavior of Internet website visitors. Google Analytics uses cookies (see above) to allow analysis of the use of the website. This involves cookies from Google itself (Google Analytics cookies) and so-called third-party cookies (doubleclick cookies). Google Analytics is regularly used only with IP addresses in a truncated format and in that respect generates no personal data. The users of our website are not identifiable. The information generated by the cookie through your use of this website is usually transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there. Your IP address is truncated beforehand by Google within the member states of the European Union or in other states party to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this website to analyze your use of the website, to compile reports on the website activities and to provide further services in connection with website usage and Internet usage, particularly functions for display advertising, such as Google Analytics demographic and interest reporting, to the website operators. Google will also transfer this information to third parties, if applicable, if this is required by law or if third parties process this data on behalf of Google. The Google Analytics demographic and interest reporting uses data obtained by Google via interest-based advertising and visitor data from third-party providers (e.g., age, gender and interests). Google will definitely not associate your IP address with other Google data. You can deactivate Google Analytics completely with the following plug-in:  <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>

You can prevent the acquisition by Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. An opt-out cookie is set to prevent the future collection of your data when visiting this website: [Deactivate Google Analytics](https://localhost/gaOptout\(\);)

Google AJAX Search API:

The JavaScript Code of the Google Inc., USA company (hereafter: Google) is loaded on our website. If you activate JavaScript in your browser and have not installed a JavaScript blocker, your browser may possibly transmit personal data to Google.

For information on the purpose and scope of data collection and the further processing and use of data by Google, as well as your rights and options for protecting your privacy, please refer to the Google data protection instructions (<https://policies.google.com/privacy>). Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement to ensure compliance with appropriate data protection levels (<https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>). To prevent the execution of JavaScript code by Google overall, you can install a JavaScript blocker (e.g., www.noscript.net).

 **12\. Security**

INFICON has implemented and employs technical and organization security measures to protect the security of data that has been transmitted to us on our Site against manipulation, loss, destruction and against access by unauthorized persons.

Our security measures are continually reviewed and improved for purposes of keeping up with technological developments.  Unfortunately, however, no collection or transmission of information over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, and therefore, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any such information.

 **13\. Routine Deletion and Blocking of Personal Data**

We process and store personal information only for the period necessary to achieve the purpose of the processing or as required by the European Directives and Regulations or any other law or regulation, such as storage periods.

If the purpose of the storage is omitted or if a storage period prescribed by the European directive and / or regulatory body expires, the processing of personal data is routinely and in accordance with statutory provisions restricted or the personal data is deleted.

 **14\. Right to Information; Updates and Modifications**

You have the right:

  * pursuant to Art. 15 GDPR, to request information about your personal data processed by us. In particular, you can provide information on the processing purposes, the category of personal data, the categories of recipients to whom your data has been or will be disclosed, the planned retention period, the right to correction, deletion, limitation of processing or objection, the existence of a right to complain, the source of their data, if not collected by us, and the existence of automated decision-making including profiling and, where appropriate, meaningful information about their details. If you are registered as a user, we also offer you the opportunity to view the data yourself and, if necessary, to delete or change it.
  * pursuant to Art. 16 GDPR, immediately demand the correction of incorrect or completion of your personal data stored by us;
  * pursuant to Art. 17 GDPR, to demand the deletion of your personal data stored by us,  unless the processing is for the exercise of the right to freedom of expression and information, for the fulfillment of a legal obligation, for reasons of the public interest or is required for the assertion, exercise or defense of legal claims;
  * pursuant to Art. 18 GDPR, to demand the restriction of the processing of your personal data, if the accuracy of the data is disputed by you or the processing is unlawful, but you reject their deletion and we no longer need the data, however, you need them to assert, exercise or defend legal claims or you have filed an objection to the processing pursuant to Art. 21 GDPR;
  * pursuant to Art. 20 GDPR, to receive your personal data provided to us in a structured, standard and machine-readable format or to request transmission to another data controller;
  * pursuant to Art. 7 para. 3 GDPR, to revoke your one-time given consent to us at any time. As a result, we are not allowed to continue the data processing based on this consent in the future;
  * pursuant to Art. 77 GDPR, to complain to a supervisory authority. As a rule, you can contact the supervisory authority of your usual place of residence for this purpose;
  * pursuant to Art. 21 GDPR, to object to the processing of your personal data, provided that your personal data, based on legitimate interests pursuant to Art. 6 (1) (1) (f) GDPR, are processed insofar as there are reasons that arise from your particular situation or the objection is directed against direct mail. In the latter case, you have a general right of objection, which is implemented by us without specifying any particular situation.

If you have any questions regarding the processing of your personal data, you can contact our data protection officer, who will also be available in case of requests for information, suggestions or complaints. The contact details of our data protection officer can be found at the end of this Privacy Statement.

 **15\. Timeliness and Changes**

We reserve the right to update or modify the terms of this Privacy Policy from time to time by publishing an updated version here. Therefore, we recommend that you check back frequently, especially before you submit any personal information to our Site, to see if this Privacy Policy has changed.  By using our Site, you acknowledge acceptance of this Privacy Policy in effect at the time of use.  

Adopted in effect as of: August 2018

 **Name and Address of the Data Controller**

The data controller within the meaning of the General Data Protection Regulation and other national data protection laws of the member states and other data protection regulations is:

INFICON Holding AG

Matthias Tröndle

Hintergasse 15B

7310 Bad Ragaz / Switzerland

Tel.: +41 81 300 4980

E-mail: [matthias.troendle@inficon.com](mailto:matthias.troendle@inficon.com)

Website: www.inficon.com

 **Questions, Suggestions, Comments**  
Please send your questions, suggestions, comments to: [matthias.troendle@inficon.com](mailto:matthias.troendle@inficon.com).

We will contact you promptly.

 **Name and Address of the Data Protection Officer**

The data protection officer of the controller is:

Urs Waelchli

c/o INFICON AG

Alte Landstrasse 6

9496 Balzers / Liechtenstein

Tel.: +423 388 3266

E-mail: [urs.waelchli@inficon.com](mailto:urs.waelchli@inficon.com)

Website: www.inficon.com
